Sheldon Hall
State University of New York at Oswego
Sheldon Hall
1979 - 1997
Papers relating to Sheldon Hall including the history of Sheldon Hall from it's construction to it's close in 1983, due to lack of funds and maintenance problems. Also, the history of Sheldon Hall, from 1983 -1997, which covers the leasing and the renovation of Sheldon Hall to " Historic Renovations, Inc. "
0.84 linear feet
State University College (Oswego, N.Y.)
State University of New York at Oswego Penfield Library 7060 State Route 104 Oswego, New York 13126-3599
2002.010.0003
Collection is open for research.
Sheldon Hall was originally built to house Oswego Normal School. First building on the current SUNY Oswego campus.
Sheldon, E. A. (Edward Austin), 1823-1897; State University College (Oswego, N.Y.); Oswego (N.Y.); Gressano, Louis; Hemink, Lynn; Henderson, Bernie; Mazzoli, Frank J.; Radley, Virginia L.; Spencer, Ralph; Stephens, Donald J.; Architects; Architecture; Buildings -- New York -- Oswego; Banquet Halls -- New York -- Oswego; Historic buildings -- New York -- Oswego; Pergolas -- New York -- Oswego; Schools -- New York -- Oswego; Oswego Normal School -- New York -- Oswego
Papers relating to Sheldon Hall including the history of Sheldon Hall from it's construction to it's close in 1983, due to lack of funds and maintenance problems. Also, the history of Sheldon Hall, from 1983 -1997, which covers the leasing and the renovation of Sheldon Hall to " Historic Renovations, Inc. " The last folder contains information pertaining to general physical plant throughout the campus
- Press Releases, 1983 - 1984 (Box-folder 01-01)
  Information packet estimating costs to run Sheldon Hall. Development bids are welcome packet, etc. 6 packets. 3-4 pages each.
- Correspondence, 1983 (Box-folder 01-02)
  Correspondence from Committee to Save, suggestions to make the hall viable again and complete history of Sheldon Hall. Maps of building layout. Memo's regarding building, to and from Dr. Lynn Hemink.
- Proposals, 1983 - 1989 (Box-folder 01-03)
  Sheldon Hall Project Packet and requests for development. List of interested developers for Sheldon Hall. 13 packets. 2-30 pages each.
- Costs for Rehabilitation, 1983 (Box-folder 01-04)
  Correspondence of support from Senator Barclay and cost of blueprints. 5 packets. 4-15 pages each.
- History + Construction, 1982 - 1983 (Box-folder 01-05)
  General Specifications The history and construction of Sheldon Hall. 6 packets. 2- 5 pages each.
- Committee to Save, 1983 - 1984 (Box-folder 01-06)
  Documents related to the movement to save Sheldon hall. Minutes of Committee to Save meeting, correspondence to President Radley, Petition to save Sheldon Hall. 4 packets. 3-5 pages each.
- Newspaper articles, 1984 - 1985 (Box-folder 01-07)
  Articles about Sheldon Hall bids, arguments for and against development.
- Correspondence, 1983 - 1984 (Box-folder 01-08)
  Correspondence from Lynne Hemink, Developer Frank Cosentino, and others showing interest in the Sheldon Hall project. 18 packets. 2 - 5 pages each.
- Lease agreements, 1984 (Box-folder 02-09)
  Draft agreement about Sheldon Hall's lease with historic renovations. 4 large packets.
- Historic Renovations, Inc., 1983 - 1984 (Box-folder 02-10)
  Copy of contract, guidlines for Sheldon Hall's rehabilitation. Survey and evaluation on building plans. 8 packets. 2-5 pages each.
- Memorial Fund ( SUCO Foundation ), 1983 - 1987 (Box-folder 02-11)
  Documents related to the purchase of Sheldon Hall by the SUCO Foundation. Booklet from Peg Lowery about Giving Initiatives.
- Packet for mailing, 1984 (Box-folder 02-12)
  Newspaper articles concerning bidding on Sheldon Hall's redevelopment. A brief history about Sheldon - 3 pages. Map of building. Invitation for proposals.
- Maintenance, 1984 (Box-folder 02-13)
  Maintenance documents establishing how much money would be saved with Sheldon's closing, OSHA standards and letter stating that Sheldon is no longer up to OSHA's standards for safety. 9 small packets. 3-4 pages each. One large packet, 47 pages, on the reported safety violations and safety needed at Sheldon for any workers - Robert Bieling sworn statement.
- Relocation of Offices, 1983 (Box-folder 02-14)
  Correspondence to Ralph Spencer from Bernie Henderson on where the new departments have been moved, since leaving Sheldon Hall. Correspondence regarding space utilization.
- Remodeling, 1985 (Box-folder 02-15)
  Various correspondence concerning developers plans to Sheldon Hall, key from Sheldon Hall. Documents related to Sheldon Hall lease with developers - Historic Renovations, Inc.
- Sheldon Inn, 1989 (Box-folder 02-16)
  Sheldon Inn Correspondence concerning development projections for Sheldon Hall. Brief 3-page history on the building. Suggestions for Inn plans. Sheldon Hall project Packet - 28 pages.
- Disbursement Committee, 1984 (Box-folder 02-17)
  Committee list, Memo to Dr. Virginia Radley, and 4 correspondences regarding disbursement.
- Contracts and Proposals, 1963 (Box-folder 02-18)
  "Contract For Remodeling Work at Sheldon Hall" 110 pages variously numbered, dated June 24, 1963. Includes forms for bidders to fill out. "Contract for: Remodeling Work at Sheldon Hall" 107 pages, variously numbered, dated September 16, 1963. Has the original signatures with bid from Louis Gressani of Louis Gressani Contractors, Inc, Notary publics, Lawyer, Insurance Agent, etc. Lists Donald J. Stephens as the NY State University Architect.
- General Physical Plant, 1970, 1989 (Box-folder 02-19)
  General Physical Plant Includes: Maintenance Department Annual Report, June 1, 1970 Comments by Director of the physical plant, Frank Mazzoli, on work projects February and March, 1989. 22 pages includes a chart on the back including: completed, backlog, man-hours available, and regular hours and overtime hours worked.